Inventory of the Cuban Freedom Committee records
Hoover Institution Archives
Cuban Freedom Committee records
1947-1993
97004
Cuban Freedom Committee.
70 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (28.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches, reports, radio broadcast transcripts, financial records, press releases, sound recordings, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to communism, political conditions and civil rights in Cuba, Cuban influence elsewhere in Latin America, and Cubans in exile in the United States, and especially to broadcasting activities of Free Cuba Radio from the United States to Cuba. Includes a few later papers of Mariada C. Arensberg (later Bourgin), executive secretary of the Cuban Freedom Committee.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1997.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
The United States Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) set up the Cuban Freedom Committee in late 1960 to sponsor anti-Castro radio broadcasts similar to those of Radio Free Europe. The committee appeared as a private activist group that solicited donations for the operation, later identified as a funding conduit for CIA domestic operations.
The Cuban Freedom Committee produced Free Radio Cuba, a stridently anti-Castro program that was broadcast before, during, and after the Bay of Pigs invasion on licensed stations in the United States and overseas including WKWF, Key West; WGBS, Miami; and Radio Swan from the Swan Islands off the coast of Honduras.
Sources: Historical Dictionary of American Propaganda, Martin J. Manning and Herbert Romerstein, Greenwood Press, Westport Ct., 2004 "Ex-Pittsburger Heads Cuban Freedom Group: Mrs. Arensberg Named Executive Secretary; Financing Broadcasts Aim," Pittsburg Post-Gazzette, April 4, 1961
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is comprised of records from Mariada C. Arensberg (later Mariada Bourgin), the executive secretary of the Cuban Freedom Committee and later the special assistant to the U.S. assistant secretary of state for education and cultural affairs. Materials include correspondence, speeches, reports, radio broadcast recordings and transcripts from Radio Free Cuba, financial records, press releases, clippings, notes, and other printed matter.
The records of the Cuban Freedom Committee and Radio Free Cuba document research efforts and the creation of and reaction to radio broadcasts to Cuba. Material includes research files on topics such as Fidel Castro, political conditions and civil rights in Cuba, the Cuban economy, Cuban propaganda, Latin American groups, Cuban society after Castro, Cuban exiles, Cuban inmates, Cuban intellectuals, Cuban schools, Cuban subversive activities in Latin America, and Cuban-Russian relations, as well as material relating to the CIA's involvement in Radio Free Cuba.
As a special assistant in the Department of State, Arensberg was in charge of its programs for women and minorities. Particularly, there is information relating to increasing the participation in international cultural exchange programs documented through correspondence, university publications, and print materials.
English and Spanish names of events and organizations were used interchangeably throughout the Cuban Freedom Committee records.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Free Cuba Radio; Radio broadcasting--Cuba.; Anti-communist movements.; Civil rights--Cuba.; Cubans--United States.; Cuba--Politics and government--1959-; Cuba--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Cuba.; Cuba--Foreign relations--Latin America.; Latin America--Foreign relations--Cuba.; Bourgin, Mariada C.
Collection Contents
- Cuba, newspaper clippings, 1961-1968 (Box 1)
  - 1961 (Box 1)
  - 1962 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1963 (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1964 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1965 (Box 2)
  - 1966 (Box 2)
  - 1967 (Box 2)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 2)
- Conference of Presidents, Punta del Este, April 1967 (Box 2)
- Laso Conference, 31 July 1967 (Box 3)
- Organization of American States (Organización de los Estados Americanos), Tri-Continental Conference: Africa, Asia, Latin America, 1966; See also box 4, 7-11 (Box 3)
- Cuba, clippings, 1960 (Box 3)
- Cuba, clippings, 1962 (Box 3)
- Venezuela, 1964-1967 (Box 3)
- Documentary summary of Sino-Soviet split, circa 1960s (Box 3)
- Régis Debray, 1967 (Box 4)
- Confederación de Trabaja, Dores de Venezuela, 2 July 1967 (Box 4)
- Haiti, 1964-1967 (Box 4)
- Dominican Republic, 1966 (Box 4)
- México, 1961-1966 (Box 4)
- Panamá, 1964-1967 (Box 4)
- Spain, 1966 (Box 4)
- Venezuela, 1964 (Box 4)
- Soviet Union and Block countries, 1964-1968 (Box 4)
- Uruguay, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
- Organization of American States (Organización de los Estados Americanos)., See also box 3, 7-11 (Box 4)
  - Tri-Continental Conference: Africa, Asia, Latin America, texts adopted at the conference and general resolutions, 3-14 January 1966 (Box 4)
  - Tri-Continental Conference, minutes of the special meeting, 24 January 1966 (Box 4)
  - Tri-Continental Conference, February 1966 (Box 4)
  - Tri-Continental Conference, Intellectuals, November 1966 (Box 4)
- Nicolaĭ Podgornyĭ, 10 January 1964 (Box 5)
- Jose Rebellon, 1962- 1963 (Box 5)
- Waldina Restano, circa 1963 (Box 5)
- Marcos Rodríguez Alfonso, 1963 (Box 5)
- Marcos Rodríguez Alfonso, series por Rene Viera, Diario de las Américas, 1964 (Box 5)
- Rolando Cubela trial, March 1966 (Box 5)
- Armando Hart, 1962-1966.; See also box 12 (Box 5)
- Algiers, 1965 (Box 5)
- Glossary of abbreviations used in the Latin American press, circa 1960s (Box 5)
- Latin America, general, 1963-1967 (Box 5)
- Brasil, 1964-1966 (Box 5)
- Augusto Martinez Sanchez, 1962-1964 (Box 5)
- Lazaro Pena, 1962-1965 (Box 5)
- Marcos Rodríguez trial, March-April 1964 (Box 5)
- Bolivia, 1963-1967 (Box 5)
- Colombia, 1965 (Box 5)
- Chile, 1965-1967 (Box 5)
- China, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
- Congo, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
- Juana Castro, 1964 (Box 6)
- Raúl Castro speeches (2 folders), 1962-1967 (Box 6)
- Carlos Rafael Rodríguez speeches (3 folders), 1962-1964 (Box 6)
- Raúl Roa speeches, 1962-1966 (Box 6)
- Jesús Soto speeches, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous (4 folders), 1962-1965 (Box 6)
- Blas Roca, 1962-1964 (Box 6)
- Organization of American States (Organización de los Estados Americanos), 1960-1967.; See also box 3-4, 8-10 (Box 7)
  - Treaties (Serie de Tratados) 9-33 (3 folders), 1960-1966 (Box 7)
  - Councils (Serie de consejo), 1961-1967 (Box 7)
- Fidel Castro speeches, 1965-1967.; See also box 9 (Box 8)
  - May 1965 (Box 8)
  - June 1965 (Box 8)
  - July-December 1965 (Box 8)
  - January-February 1966 (Box 8)
  - March-April 1966 (Box 8)
  - July-September 1966 (Box 8)
  - December 1966 (Box 8)
  - January-February 1967 (Box 8)
  - 1967 (Box 8)
- Juana Castro speeches, 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - 1964 (Box 8)
  - 1965 (Box 8)
- Osmany Cienfuegos speeches, 1962-1966 (Box 8)
- Faure Chomon speeches, 1962-1966 (Box 8)
- Organization of American States (Organización de los Estados Americanos), Treaties 1-8, 1947-1966.; See also box 3-4, 7, 9-11 (Box 8)
- Cuba Laboral, FORDC (3 folders), 1964-1967 (Box 9)
- Press information on Cuba, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
- Organization of American States Inter-american Commission on Human Rights (Organización de los Estados Americanos Comisión Interamericana de Derechos Humanos), 1963-1967.; See also box 3-4, 7-8, 10-11 (Box 9)
- Index to Castro's speeches, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
- Efigenio Almeijeiras, 1966 (Box 9)
- Fidel Castro and Richard Eder, 5 July 1964 (Box 9)
- Faustino Calcines, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
- Fidel Castro, clippings, 1959 (Box 9)
- Comité Central, 1965 (Box 9)
- Fidel Castro speeches, 1964-1965.; See also box 8 (Box 9)
  - January-May 1964 (Box 9)
  - June July 1964 (Box 9)
  - August-September 1964 (Box 9)
  - October 1964 (Box 9)
  - November-December 1964 (Box 9)
  - January-April 1965 (Box 9)
- Organization of American States (Organización de los Estados Americanos), 1954-1966.; See also box 3-4, 7-9, 11 (Box 10)
  - First Conference of Tri-Continental, November 1966 (Box 10)
  - Inter-American defense board, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
  - First special Inter-American conference, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Conference in Punta del Este, Uruguay, April 1967 (Box 10)
  - The meetings of consultation, their origin, significance and role in Inter-American relations, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Inter-American Peace treaties and conventions, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Convention on diplomatic asylum, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Inter-American Commission on peace, eighth meeting of foreign ministries, January 1962 (Box 10)
  - Second Special Inter-American conference, Río de Janeiro, 1965 (Box 10)
  - First Special Inter-American conference, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
- Alliance for Progress (Alianza para el Progreso) (3 folders), 1962-1967 (Box 10)
- José Llanusa speeches, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
- Juan Martinello speeches, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
- Organization of American States Security Council (Organización de los Estados Americanos Comisión Especial de Seguridad), 1966 (Box 10)
- Cuba Laboral, FORDC (2 folders), 1965; See also Cuba Laboral, FORDC in box 9 (Box 10)
- Cuban refugees, 1963-1965.; See also box 12 (Box 11)
- Organization of American States, 1960-1967.; See also box 3-4, 7-9 (Box 11)
  - Annual report of the secretary general, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1967 (Box 11)
  - Clippings, 1962-1967 (Box 11)
  - Twelfth meeting, 24 September 1967 (Box 11)
- Cuba biographies, circa 1965 (Box 11)
- Organization of American States (Organización de los Estados Americanos), 1964, 1967; See also box 3-4, 7-9 (Box 11)
  - First reunion, 1964 (Box 11)
  - Meeting in Punta del Este 12-14, April 1967 (Box 11)
  - Foreign ministers meeting, 21 July 1964 (Box 11)
- Che Guevara speeches (2 folders), 1962-1965 (Box 12)
- Emulación Socialista, 18 March 1963 (Box 12)
- Television interviews, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
- Three Cubans accused as spies for the CIA, 1963 (Box 12)
- Fidel Castro and Robert Williams, 1962 (Box 12)
- Armando Hart, 1962-1963.; See also box 5 (Box 12)
- Osvaldo Dorticos T. speeches, 1963-1967 (Box 12)
- Vilma Espin speeches, 1962-1966 (Box 12)
- "Intercambio Comercial entre Cuba y URSS,", 1962 (Box 12)
- Eloy Gutiérrez Menoyo, interview, February 1965 (Box 12)
- Mikoian interview, 1960 (Box 12)
- Free Cuba News citizens committee, 1963-1966 (Box 12)
- Principle figures of the Cuban government and Communist Party of Cuba, 1967 (Box 12)
- Cuba, general, 1960 (Box 12)
- Cuban refugees, 1960-1967.; See also box 11 (Box 12)
- Council for Latin America exchange, 1966-1967 (Box 13)
- Free Cuba News Citizens Committee, 1963-1967.; See also box 12 (Box 13)
- Weekly Reports on Cuba, in English (7 folders), 1963-1968 (Box 13)
- Latin American Monitoring Service, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
  - January-October 1962 (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - January-November 1963 (6 folders) (Box 14)
- Free Cuba News Citizens Committee, 1963-1966 (Box 14)
- Latin America Report, Free Cuba News, 1965-1967 (Box 14)
- Informe Sobre Cuba, serial, 1963-1966 (Box 14)
- Latin American Monitoring Service (7 folders), May 1966-August 1967 (Box 15)
- "Resumen de noticias de Cuba" (6 folders), May 1966-July 1967 (Box 15)
- United States Information Agency, Chronology of Cuban Events, 1963, 23 October 1964 (Box 15)
- Cuba in 1965, United States Information Agency, 17 January 1966 (Box 15)
- "Resumen de noticias de Cuba,", 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - April-May 1965 (Box 16)
  - January-April 1966 (2 folders) (Box 16)
- Latin American Monitoring Service, 1964-1966 (Box 16)
  - July-November 1964 (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - January 1965-April 1966 (7 folders) (Box 16)
- Che Guevara materials, 1965 (Box 16)
- Personalidades Cubanas (Cuba en el Exilio), eighth edition, por Fermín Peraza Sarausa, 1965 (Box 17)
- Of Human Rights, Georgetown University, 1981-1986 (Box 17)
- Free Cuba Radio, miscellaneous, 1960-1967 (Box 17)
- Latin American Monitoring Service (Box 17)
  - June-December 1963 (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - March-June 1964 (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - June 1965-April 1966 (4 folders) (Box 17)
- Tri-Continental Conference: Africa, Asia, Latin America, 1963-1967 (Box 18)
- Vietnam, 1965-1967 (Box 18)
- Gramma, Cuban newspaper, 1966 (Box 18)
- "Ley de Justicia Laboral,", October 1964 (Box 18)
- Facts on Cuba Pre-Castro, 1953-1956 (Box 18)
- "Respuesta de la Republica Popular China, a los Planteamiento del Comandante Fidel Castro,", 2 January 1966 (Box 18)
- Cuban labor leaders, 1966-1967 (Box 18)
- Judith Williams, NBC, undated (Box 18)
- Universities, 1964-1990 (Box 18)
- Partners of the Americas, SER, 1961-1992 (Box 18)
- United States International Communications Agency, seminar, photographs, circa 1960-1970 (Box 18)
- Cubans in the United States, Carlos Ripoll, book, 1987 (Box 18)
- Económico sobre La Ley de Reforma Agraria, Informe Técnico, Instituto Nacional de Reforma Económica, 1959 (Box 18)
- Permits to solicit funds from radio and television, correspondence and permits, 1961-1962 (Box 19)
- Cuban Freedom Committee, miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 19)
- Mariada C. Arensberg correspondence (2 folders), 1961-1967 (Box 19)
- Tri-Continental Conference: Africa, Asia, Latin America (2 folders), 1966 (Box 19)
- "Reforma Urbana,", November 1965 (Box 19)
- Time Magazine, "Cuba: Caning the Students,", 18 March 1966 (Box 19)
- Florida territorial waters act, 1964-1965 (Box 19)
- Miscellaneous, MCA, 1962-1967 (Box 19)
- Cuban exile groups, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
- Guantanamo, naval base, 1962-1966 (Box 19)
- Cuba, food rationing, 1962-1967 (Box 19)
- Economic boycott, 1964-1967 (Box 19)
- "Artistas Cubanos en Exilio,", 1965 (Box 19)
- Cuba, terror and atrocities, 1963-1964 (Box 19)
- Cuban caves, 1962-1966 (Box 19)
- Cuba, Department of State, white paper, 1961 (Box 19)
- Cuban Freedom Committee radio broadcast sound recordings, open reel tapes, 1962-1963 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a tres jóvenes, llegaron cinco en un bote, la situación cubana respecto al adoctrinamiento en las escuelas, en caso de los 'estudiantes' norteamericanos que visitaron a Cuba, la juventud cubana no es comunista," WGBS, 29 September 1963 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a matrimonio y otro, Uruguay, la situación en Cuba, la invasión rusa a Cuba, el estado de terror, dentro de la embajada de Uruguay, palabras de una madre a Cuba," WKWF, 14 June 1963 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a Carlos M. Llueh de Unidad Fraternal Cubana e Internacional, Cubanos de la raza de color en el exilio," WGBS, 11 August 1963 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a carpintero, vino en bote," WGBS, 9 August 1962 (Box 20)
  - Program special, "Excerpts of Voice of Castro," Cayo Hueso, 9 September 1963 (Box 20)
  - "Documental comunismo, afirmaciones del déspota de no ser comunista (en su propia voz), afirmaciones del déspota de ser comunista (en su propia voz), comentarios," Cayo Hueso, 26 July 1962 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista Colono de Oriente, despojo de los colonos, la zafra azucarera, causas del fracaso, industria lechera y de carne, encuentro entre patriotas y fuerzas de la dictadura," WKWF, 10 June 1962 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista Capitán, escape y travesía, atropellos en Cuba, alzados en las villas, relato de un crimen, relatos diversos,", 23 June 1962 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a Dr. Fleites y Sr. Veciana sobre los ataques a Cuba roja," WKWF, Cayo Hueso, 2-Apr-63 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a dos cubanos de veintiuno llegados, después del ciclón Flora, llegaron hoy," WKWF, 17 October 1963 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista (tres), escapados en bote, situaciones en Matanzas, crímenes del régimen, llamada a Cuba, entrevista a maestra ingles y ex-funcionario, adoctrinamiento, caso de INIT, MINFAR, palabras ingles," Radio Progreso, 26 July 1962 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a estudiante universitaria," WGBS, 14 September 1962 (Box 20)
  - "Documental penetración soviética, palabras del déspota y comentarios,", 19 August 1962 (Box 20)
  - "Entrevista a bote 'dos Mamas,' un grupo, joven llevado a una granja, este joven declina sobre el trabajo como castigo en las granjas rojas,", 3 October 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a Juanita Castro," WRUL, 31 October 1965 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a Señora Ernestina Romero, llego en el African pilota,", 28 December 1962 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a escapado en bote, para los días de Navidad, el racionamiento de los alimentos de Pascuas, situación general de Cuba,", 22 December 1962 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a tres mujeres en bote, niños, hablan de la situación en Cuba. Los alimentos que faltan, el terror, los trabajadores para en seguir algo," WKWF, 26 July 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Juanita Castro ante el veintiséis de Julio, palabras pronunciadas por la Señorita Juanita Castro sobre la fecha traicionada por el Tirano de Cuba,", circa 1960 (Box 21)
  - "Comentario de la Señorita Juanita Castro sobre el 'Aviso Preventivo,'", circa 1960 (Box 21)
  - "Christmas in Cuba, A message to the American People at Christmas, by E. Sánchez", 17 December 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a María Fernández, maestra, bote, el adoctrinamiento en la escuela cubana, el papel del magisterio en este momento, los que delatan a los maestros," WKWF, 10 June 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Palabras Monseñor Boza Masvidal, Sánchez Torrento," WGBS, WKWF, 7 April 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a grupo de once cubanos, las causas por las cuales salen los cubanos humildes de Cuba, los campos de concentración y los castigos a los trabajadores, el terror entre el pueblo,", 26 August 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a Cubano que regreso, había ido a Cuba en 1962, engañado por el régimen de Castro," WKWF, 15 January 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a Dr. Fleites y Sr. Veciana," WGBS, 2 April 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a Juan Manuel Salado-Lanchero, vino en un bote, la situación de cuba, religioso evangélico llamada a los Cubanos fuera de Cuba, palabras del padrino que los trajo, como son tratados los pescadores," WKWF, 7 September 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista a Francisco Sánchez Pérez, color, vino en bote," WGBS, 25 August 1963 (Box 21)
  - "Entrevista, invasión de dos presas políticas de la cárcel de Guanajay, estado de las presas políticas, narración de la fuga, palabras finales a sus hermanas presas en Cuba,", 11 August 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista a Medico Dr. Carrio," Caya Hueso, 2 September 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Documental 'Lucha de Clases,'" Caya Hueso, 26 October 1963 (Box 22)
  - "Un medico que vino en bote. La situación general del país, el estado sanitario, las medicinas producto del cambio de los prisioneros de Girni," WGBS, 3 February 1963 (Box 22)
  - "Señora Rosa Pérez y Señorita M. Pellerano (Amas de Casa),", 9 August 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Escapados Alemania Cubanos 'Odisea en el Mar,'" WKWF, 13 August 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista miembro clandestinidad, entrevista pilotos cubanos llegados en avión soviético,", 23 August 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista a Varias Madres Cubanas,", 16 August 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista a un comerciante de Guantánamo, la situación de los comerciantes en Cuba, como es la persecución comunista en Guantánamo, sus nombres los que han sido matados, alocución al pueble de Cuba y OEA,", 20 June 1963 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista a un chofer que llego en un bote,", 23 December 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista a Frank Hidalgo, carpintero, vino en bote, las casas que se construyen en Cuba para rusos y milicianos. Nunca las dieron a los campesinos. Lo que puede pasar el que se niegue a trabajar para el estado comunista. Lo que piensan los campesinos,", 26 August 1963 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista a repatriado José Bernardovino en un bote con su esposa y un hijo. Hace un año y pico se fue a Cuba 'engaña de' por la propaganda comunista. Como fue tratado allá. Se hizo pasar por comunista y 'se les fue.' Se dirige a los que puedan pensar como peuso el. Vivía en: Neptuno 112, Habana,", 31 July 1963 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista Pte. abogados (para pasar día del abogado que es el viernes ocho), Contiene: Régimen de derecho en Cuba, tribunales de justicia, liberta des individuales, arenga Cuba y América," WKWF, 8 June 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Entrevista a Raúl Quintas, vino en bote, sobre los comtes de Chivatos,", 27 September 1963 (Box 22)
- Miríada Bourgin, senior advisor for minority programs, International Communication Agency (4 folders), 1974-1984 (Box 23)
- Mariada C. Arensberg correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 23)
- Cuba in the Nineties: A Special Report by Freedom House, 1991 (Box 23)
- Black colleges, minority program, United States International Communication Agency, 1974-1986 (Box 23)
- Phelps-Stokes fund, 1972-1982 (Box 23)
- Cuban economy, 1964-1965 (Box 23)
- álvaro de Villa poetry, 1961-1963 (Box 23)
- Tri-Continental Conference: Africa, Asia, Latin America, 1966 (Box 23)
- "Cuba: Land of Opportunity, Playland of the Americas," Pan-America Magazine, 1959 (Box 23)
- Cuban Freedom Committee fundraising campaign, 1961 (Box 24)
- Cuba Today, Cuban Freedom Committee pamphlets, 1961-1966 (Box 24)
- The Bell of Dawn, by Ernesto Diaz Rodríguez, 1989 (Box 24)
- Caribbean, úNICA, 1976-1982 (Box 24)
- External Information and Cultural Relations Programs, United States Information Agency, Office of Research and Assessment, 1973 (Box 24)
- United States Information Agency, Office of Private Sector Programs, 1981-1983 (Box 24)
- Cuban Freedom Committee report by Robert R. Mullen and Company, Public Relations, 1963 (Box 24)
- Dangerous Dialogue: Attacks on Freedom of Expression in Miami's Cuban Exile Community, Americas Watch, The Fund for Free Expression, a division of Human Rights Watch, 1992 (Box 24)
- Council series, volume II, Council of the Organization of American States, 1966 (Box 24)
- Organización Continental Latinoamericana de Estudiantes, Tri-Continental conference, 1966-1967 (Box 24)
- Latin American Solidarity Organization, circa 1960s (Box 24)
- "El Imperio de la Ley en Cuba," International Commission of Jurists, 1962 (Box 25)
- "El Corazón con que Vivo," Armando Valladares, 1983 (Box 25)
- The Cuban University Under the Revolution, The Cuban American National Foundation, 1988 (Box 25)
- Military service law, 1963 (Box 25)
- Agencia de Informaciones Periodísticas, éxodo, 1965 (Box 25)
- Cuban subversive activities in Latin America, circa 1960s (Box 25)
- "La Agonía de Cuba: Calendario para 1965," editorial, Agencia de Informaciones Periodsticas, 1959-1965 (Box 25)
- Letters from Mariada Arensberg, Radio Cuba Libre, 1961 (Box 25)
- Letters from Mariada Arensberg, Radio Cuba Libre, 1966 (Box 25)
- "Cuba: The Castro Generation," ABC News, 4 March 1977 (Box 25)
- Moral Education in the Age of Reagan, David Bromwich, circa 1980s (Box 25)
- Projections of Cuba after Fidel Castro, 1967-1993 (Box 25)
- "Family of Man," sketch, undated (Box 25)
- Cuban Freedom Committee, press releases, 1963 (Box 26)
- Testimony of Mariada Arensberg for Cuban Freedom Committee, "Winning the Cold War: The United States Ideological Offensive,", 1963 (Box 26)
- Cuban Radio propaganda, 1961-1966 (Box 26)
- "Five Years of Castro's Cuba," commentary, January 1964 (Box 26)